I will call to order the regular City Council meeting for Tuesday May 5th, 2026.
I have two oath of office administered for bless Parker the man.
I bless Parker.
Do solemnly swear or affirm.
That I will support obey and defend the Constitution of the United States.
That I will affirm.
And the Constitution of the State of Oklahoma.
And that I will not knowingly receive directly or indirectly.
Any money or other valuable thing.
For the performance or non-performance.
Of any act or duty pertaining to my office.
Other than the compensation allowed by law.
I further swear or affirm.
that I will faithfully discharge, according to the best of my ability, the duties of my office during such time as I serve as the Mayor of the City of Miami, Oklahoma and the Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Miami Special Utility Authority of the City of Miami, Oklahoma.
Congratulations. If you'll sign it, I'll take it.
Three public input unscheduled personal appearances. We have none.
For a claims list.
Hi, for be minutes from the April 21 2026 regular meeting.
Motion to approve.
Hi, for see letter of support from the city of Miami for a Department of Commerce emergency solutions grant for the Community Crisis Center.
Stephanie.
Hi, I'm Kelsey with the Community Crisis Center.
We're asking you guys to sign the certification of local government approval for nonprofits we can apply for the emergency solutions grant.
The Community Crisis Center is a local nonprofit that serves victims of domestic violence sexual assault stalking and human trafficking.
We have had this grant for about 30 years.
We're a sub recipient of the Community Action Associates out of J.
So there is not a fiscal responsibility or oversight responsibility for the city.
But it's you guys are proving that you're okay with these services operating within the city of Miami, and that it fits into the regional plan to address homelessness.
I make a motion to approve.
Thank you.
For the contract between Doc services incorporated in the city of Miami as recommended by the senior center center incorporated and authorized the city manager to sign.
Good evening.
Before you tonight is a contract recommended by the Miami senior center board regarding the use of the senior center commercial kitchen by Doc services.
Currently Doc's utilizes the kitchen to prepare meals for our senior population, which is a service we value and want to continue to support.
However, at this time they are not paying rent or utilities for this facility prior to the city taking over operations of the senior center is supported this program by contributing 12,000 annually to the senior center on behalf of Doc's along with providing utility credits.
Since the city assumed operations we've taken on the full cost of maintaining the facility grounds and staffing.
As you can imagine those costs are significant and continuing to absorb them without cost sharing is not sustainable long term.
The contract before you tonight is intended to formalize this relationship and establish a more balanced approach. It allows us to continue supporting meal services for our seniors while also ensuring the city is being fiscally responsible.
We would like to recommend approval of this contract with the adjustment to the terms and rent.
Commencing on June 1, 2026 and terminating on May 31, 2027 and authorizing the city manager to sign.
Second.
For a discussion and possible vote on library procedures for annual state library report as recommended by the library board.
So every year we turn in a report to the state library and each year they ask us to do a different aspect of it.
And this year is just having you guys put eyes on our policies and procedures and approving them.
We haven't changed anything since the last time they were presented.
It's just a step we have to take for our annual report.
I make a motion to approve.
Thank you.
For resolution CC 2026 dash 08 codification of the Miami Oklahoma code of ordinances to include supplement 23.
This is not here.
I'll go and speak.
This is just the codification.
We do this every quarter.
Make a motion.
We approve.
Hi.
Order in its 2026 dash 10 rezoning certain property within the city limits from RS 5 to RM 2 located at lot 15 a lot 16 block five of Johnson addition Travis a Casey properties real estate which is to rezone these lots.
There's not an address, because it is a vacant lot, two lots.
And they're proposing to rezone it
as residential multifamily.
RM2, the planning commission recommends rezoning it.
He's proposing to build a quadplex on this lot.
Make a motion to approve.
Second.
Jones.
Easton.
Aye.
Barz.
Donovan.
Aye.
Parker.
4-8, ordinance 2026-11, rezoning
certain property within the city limits from RS5 to RM2,
located on the north half of lot 221 and all of lot 222,
the Belmont addition.
Same thing.
There was a house on this lot.
David Wired bought the lots, demoed a house.
He's built a home on, there were four lots
he initially bought, demoed the house,
built a lot on a lot and a half.
And on the north lot and a half, he wants to,
he's proposing building a duplex.
Resonance RM2, residential multifamily,
and the planning commission recommends that it be rezoned.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Aye.
Easton.
Jones.
Aye.
Barz.
Parker.
Aye.
Thank you.
4-I, authorize the city manager to negotiate and execute
contract with Fuller Tubb Bickford, Warmington,
and Panache for financial audit and claim.
Good evening, board.
So yes, so recent allegations regarding the mayor
have been brought to my attention.
And my job as the manager is to look
into these allegations.
So with this, these allegations
include concerns related to conduct, use of city
resources, retaliation of possible open records,
and Open Meeting Act issues.
Because of this, I recommend bringing in an outside
professional to review the concerns
and provide an independent assessment to the board.
I'm requesting your authorization
to move forward with the firm for these services.
Make a motion to approve.
Parker.
Barnes.
Aye.
Jones.
Easton.
Aye.
Dunkel.
5-A, nomination to appoint T. Is that right?
Taya.
Taya Woods to the Miami Library Board term
to expire 2-4, 2029.
Make a motion to approve.
I'll second.
Barnes.
Aye.
Jones.
Easton.
Aye.
Dunkel.
6, other new business, if any, which is business
as opposed to this agenda.
7, staff reports.
8, mayor council community announcements.
I have one.
Last meeting, we forgot to make an announcement
about our city communicators, our 911 dispatch.
It was communication week that week.
And we missed it.
But all of our communicators, our dispatchers,
do a fabulous job.
The 911 dispatchers are great people.
They represent our police department well
and all the emergency management and the emergency
people in the county.
So I think they deserve a little recognition.
So I wanted to thank them for what they do.
While we're at it, might as well go
and throw the firefighters in, too.
Because yesterday was International Firefighter Day 2.
So I think our city does a really good job.
9, city manager communications.
Yes, sir.
All right.
10, this meeting will now be dismissed
from this council chamber and reconvened
in the staff room for the executive session.
Make a motion.
Second.
Smith.
Aye.
Barnes.
Dunkel.
Aye.
Parker.
This meeting will now be reconvened here
in the council chambers.
Declare us out, please.
I'll declare us out of the executive session at 6.47.
Make a motion to approve.
Yeah, we just have to be declared out.
We're good.
You ready?
So based on the item of discussion of the executive
session, I want to make the following motions.
First motion is I want to make a motion that we
increase, give the city manager the 3% increase
that we discussed.
Can I get a second?
A second.
Sure.
I quit a think about it.
Jones.
Aye.
Dunkel.
Parker.
Aye.
Next motion I want to move is regarding our city judge.
Based on comments in the executive session,
I'd like to move that we extend the contract
with a 3% increase for our city judge.
Second.
Debs.
Aye.
Jones.
Dunkel.
Aye.
Parker.
OK.
Last motion, I move that at the request of the city
attorney that we engage in an independent investigation
into the issue she raised, as well as financial allegations
that have been presented to the city manager,
and that the city manager be authorized to sign off
to negotiate the contract.
Second.
Debs.
Aye.
Barnes.
Jones.
Aye.
Dunkel.
Item 13, adjournment.
Motion.
Second.
I'm sorry.
New motion.
Dunkel.
Aye.
And you're seconded.
I didn't.
Sorry.
Here.
Dunkel.
Aye.
Barnes.
Jones.
Aye.
Debs.
Parker.
Aye.